[intense music]
[metal clanking]
[sizzles]
Ah, brother.
Back sooner than expected.
How went the south?
How do you think it went?
Everything below
the Jagged Divide
has either submitted
to the army of the Five,
or was razed to the ground
by the power of Shatterspin.
But don't take my word for it.
[scoffs]
Who's this pathetic beast?
A souvenir I collected
on my travels.
Believe it or not,
there's a tribe down there
who considers this to be
a great champion.
Speak, wretch.
Tell them of my glory.
Of our glory.
[growls]
How could you?
The evil you've done
to my people!
[laughs]
Listen, whelp,
what you call evil,
we know as strength.
And what was done
to your people,
done across the Wyldness,
will soon be done
to every realm of creation.
Prepare, my fellow conquerors.
Soon, we walk the realms.
[dragons roaring]
Hm. Something's coming
from the East.
Don't worry, my brother.
It will not be long now.
He must be crushed.
Oh, he will be.
Just as his ancestors
once were.
And the long-delayed plans
of the Forbidden Five
will finally unfold.
♪ Lost in the unknown
So much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise! ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja
For what's right! ♪
[flames roaring]
[light music]
-Look out!
-Ugh!
Ugh. I don't care
for being jostled about
like a sack of beets.
But I really don't care
for getting crushed.
So, thank you,
for your timely intervention,
young lady.
You know us Ninja,
we're all about helping others,
is what they keep telling me.
I wonder what could have caused
that brick to fall like that.
Meh, sometimes bricks fall.
Probably no one set that up
as a prank or anything.
Hey-hey, bet
an important guy like you
has major urgent stuff
to do, huh?
Yes, my duties
are quite indispensable.
I'd better get on with them.
Ha. Switched with a fake
and that old grump
never even noticed.
The being-crushed-by-a-brick
prank works again!
The Lava-Tides used to love it.
And it rarely ever
decimated their entire village.
There's gotta be some clues
to Bleckt's crimes in--
[gasps] Huh?
What language is this?
It's gibberish!
Master Wu?! Is it--
Is it really you?
[doors bang open]
Master Wu, where'd you go?
Cole, look!
[mysterious music]
[Cole]
More Portal Gates?
[Arin]
Is that the Cloud Kingdom?
Guess we know
where that gate goes.
[Cole]
That looks like Mysterium.
And there's
the Land of Lost Things.
And Ninjago, our home.
[Cole] ...fourteen,
fifteen, sixteen.
Huh, one gate
for each of the realms?
-[Master Wu] Yes.
-[Cole, Arin gasp]
Master Wu?
It's really you, isn't it?
Yes.
We've missed you so much!
What happened to you
in the Merge?
Are you-- are you departed?
And why are you
suddenly appearing now?!
Horns.
Horns? He doesn't mean...
[Cole]
He does.
[Arin] The crowns
of the murdered dragons!
Wait, Master Wu!
Ras told me
you caused the Merge.
Did you?
Arin, Ras is a liar.
There's no way
Master Wu would ever--
I need to know!
Did you cause the Merge?
Yes.
Huh?
[whooshing]
That-- that can't be right.
Everything I thought I knew...
it's all wrong.
Okay. I'm trying
for twice as far this time.
And-- Poof!
[coughing]
How does Cinder live like this?
-[coughs]
-Hydration recommended.
[coughs] Thanks, Zane.
So, did I get twice as far?
You actually appear to
have gone slightly backwards.
Argh! That jerk Cinder
made it look so easy,
but nothing's working!
I can't Quake like Frak,
or use Elemental Reflex
like Zur.
I have their powers,
why can't I be
like any of them?
I think that's the problem,
Sora.
You're trying to be like them.
Uh, yeah! What else can I do?
You can be you.
Being me isn't great
right now.
My best friend hates me.
My Spinjitzu
still won't spin-jitz.
And an evil loser
from ancient times
is about to trash me
in front of a live audience.
Sora, I've seen you do things
no one else could ever do.
Stop trying to
use Elemental Powers
the way everyone else did.
Think of how only Sora
would use them.
And how's that?
I don't know.
But I look forward
to finding out.
I think the time
for coaching is over.
Be right back. There's
someone I need to talk to.
I got your note.
What note?
Look, I don't understand
what's going on with you,
Jordana,
but I want to tell you,
I'm sorry.
I didn't remember you
from when we
were in school together.
I know that upset you and
made you feel unimportant.
Me and my friend Arin
have been--
I just--
I wish I hadn't been
so wrapped up in my own stuff.
I wish I'd remembered you.
School was a really lonely
time in my life,
and I could have used a friend.
Maybe we both could have.
So, I'm sorry.
[scoffs] Pathetic.
What is this? Clown language?!
Ugh!
This language is Devonian,
like me.
Master Zur?
Wait, you can talk?
Of course. Why would you
think otherwise?
I've never heard you
say anything.
Just grunts and harsh looks.
Plus, I'd expect your voice
to sound more...
I don't know, evil-ish?
My kind are extremely shy.
But because of our appearance,
there are those who
make false assumptions
and spread rumors about us.
Devonians are renowned
for our kindness, actually.
So, you can actually read this?
Yes, it is a ancient form
of my language,
from the early days
of our history.
It must still be used here
in the City of Temples.
I can help you translate
this book, if you would like.
[crowd cheering]
Ah. Today's just
another normal day, I guess?
Wrong! Today is
the most important day
in the history of all time
and forever!
The final championship
of the greatest Tournament ever
Gamesmastered!
-[cheering]
-[fireworks exploding]
In this corner, Sora,
coached by her Ninja teacher,
Master Lloyd Garmadon!
[cheering]
And in this corner, Nokt,
coached by his commander,
Lord Ras of the Wyldness.
[cheering]
With this final match,
the Tournament will end
just like it started:
One-on-one combat!
Last one standing wins it all!
Time to go "be myself,"
or whatever.
Let the game begin!
[cheering]
[grunts] Ah!
Ugh.
[gasps, murmurs]
I have no idea how you even
made it this far, girl.
But I promise you, you've
never faced anyone like me.
I faced parents like you.
I faced a whole realm like you.
[yawns] Is your sob story
over yet?
Straight for the Shatterspin,
folks!
Looks like this match might end
before it really gets started.
A little ice?
Please.
[rumbling]
I do not understand.
Why is she combining
Frak's quake power
with my ice power?
[pounding]
And now Elemental Reflex power?
I don't know,
but it looks like something
no one else would try.
[explosion]
Aah!
Whoa! Somehow,
Sora created a barrier
that vibrated exactly counter
to Shatterspin.
Can you believe how good
my games are?
Finish this, you fool!
Throw everything else
you've got at her!
[explosion]
[grunts, coughs]
[zaps]
[grunts]
Power after power,
blow after blow!
Are you not entertained?!
[cheering]
Lloyd, we found them!
Found what?
The missing horns
of the dead dragons.
Cole and I found them.
-Where?
-They're in another Monastery.
Jordana gave us a message
that led us to them.
Jordana? Does that prove
Ras is behind all this?
I think so. We know
he was meeting with Bleckt.
But I don't know what he plans
to do with the horns.
He's determined to get control
of all the Elemental Powers
in this game.
He's gotta be planning
to use the powers
and the horns together
to get to the Source Dragons.
You and Zane, go back and
get those horns out of there.
Ras can't use 'em
if he can't find them.
I'll stay to coach Sora.
She's gotta win this game.
There's something else.
We saw the ghost of Master Wu
in the Monastery.
What?
He said he caused the Merge.
What? That-- that's impossible.
Lloyd, it's true.
[Sora yells]
We can't let Ras win.
Arin, Zane, get those horns
out of there!
Come on, Zane.
[menacing music]
[both grunting with effort]
Nokt should have won by now.
He cannot fail me.
[grunting]
[yells]
[grunts]
Ugh.
There's nothing you can do
that I can't do better, kid!
Sora! Remember,
if you can't outfight him,
outsmart him!
What's that thing?
Probably not a fashion choice.
You think you defeat me
with a bumble-bee?
[buzzes]
-[grunts]
-[zapping]
Looks like it's all over,
folks!
[cheering]
[grunts]
Ugh!
Wait. What?
Oh! Lucky for Nokt,
the arena suddenly shifts
in his favor!
Expect the unexpected, folks!
We didn't program
the floor to move
in the final match, did we?
Not sure.
But isn't giving the crowd
high drama what you want?
Well, yeah, I guess.
[grunts]
[both grunting with effort]
Ah!
[Roby]
Coming back from behind,
Nokt hits Sora with Shatterspin
before she can react!
And with only one player
left standing,
this tournament
has a new champion.
Nokt is the winner!
[crowd cheering]
[fireworks exploding]
[cheering]
You were amazing out there.
Better than me.
Than nearly every
Elemental Master ever.
But Ras is gonna have control
of all the powers now.
Let's hope Arin and Zane
manage to get those horns.
And so, for the final time
in these games,
I'll transfer powers
with the Element Cup.
Whoop-whoop!
And now, the Victory Ceremony
to declare
a new Champion of the Sources!
[crowd cheering]
[Wyldfyre]
Objection!
[crowd gasps]
What? You can't object
to the victory ceremony.
You clearly know nothing
of the ancient rites!
Okay, then, "point of order"?
That's not a thing either!
Uh, "time out"?
No, no, no!
These games have been rigged!
-[crowd gasps]
-What?
-That's so unfair.
-I don't understand.
[gasps] Vile slander!
How dare you impugn the honor
of the age-old
Tournament of Sources!
For shame!
I dare 'cause
I've got your ledger!
And I can read it,
thanks to my new best-bud, Zur!
[growls] What?
The menu from the banquet?
The ol' swapped-with-a-menu
prank! Classic!
Bleckt here is such
a stickler for ledgers,
he kept detailed notes
on everything about the games,
including his own crimes.
Like him conspiring with Ras!
[gasps, murmurs]
It's all here. Check it out!
Bleckt sent the attack bots
to get rid of Ras's
strongest competition:
us Ninja and Zur.
He even sent a fake one
against Ras
to throw off suspicions.
Bleckt's been
rigging the games!
Nothing too obvious,
but always slightly in favor
of Ras' team.
It's true. It's all in here.
He's the reason the Ninja
didn't get their invites
in the first place.
And Zeatrix was actually right,
Uncle Bleckt was trying
to sideline her.
The honor of the games
is like you're whole thing,
Uncle B.
What would make you
do something like this?
Because of you!
You simpleton!
You infantile half-wit!
When my stupid brother
put you in charge,
I knew you'd ruin the games
with all your zang-toot ideas!
It was the only way to
save the games from total ruin!
Once I helped Ras win,
he'd get rid of you.
And then, I would be
the new Gamesmaster,
and dignity would be restored!
First of all,
it's "stang-zoot."
Uncle Bleckt, you are mega,
reverse, negative stang-zoot!
[boos, yelling]
[clears throat]
In light of this,
I declare the Victory Ceremony
canceled.
Security!
[warbles]
In light of that,
I un-cancel it!
[building yell]
[gasps]
[grunting]
Finally. The powers
I've always deserved!
Good. Time for
the next phase of the plan.
Actually, change of plans.
I don't work for you anymore,
Ras.
[grumbles, gasps]
There's many things
I've come to hate about you.
One of them is how clever
you think you are.
You put a technological
control collar on me,
then you sent me to fight the
Elemental Master of Technology?
He is kind of slow
on the uptake,
isn't he, brother?
"Brother"?
Rox of the Forbidden Five?
[Jordana/Rox]
Nokt's physical body
escaped the Nether Space
that day.
But you never realized
my soul escaped
to the nearest form
I could find.
Not the body
I would have picked,
but good enough
for my brother and I
to hunt some dragons.
[growls]
[roars]
[clangs]
Dragons?
Ras, you really didn't know?
Why did you kill
those three dragons?
They did nothing to you.
For the crowns, of course.
With enough Dragon Ivory,
and a multitude
of Elemental Powers...
we don't need
a Blood Moon ritual
to bring back the rest
of the Forbidden Five!
[roars]
You'll do no such thing.
[intense music]
[crowd chatters worriedly]
[bongs]
You will go with me
to the Cauldron of Realms
and complete my Master's will,
or you will be crushed.
[laughs] Oh, Ras.
Did you forget where
you got those masks from?
Did you forget
who created them?
And you've barely even
scratched the surface
of their true powers.
[worried chatter]
Finish them!
Every single one of them!
[intense music]